Guide to the Gary Hickling Collection on Lotte Lehmann ARS.0002
Stanford Archive of Recorded Sound
Gary Hickling Collection on Lotte Lehmann
1926- 1995
Gary Hickling
6 linear ft. (15 boxes)
Stanford Archive of Recorded Sound Stanford University Libraries Stanford, California 94305-3076
Includes correspondence and research notes related to Hickling's discography of Lehmann performances; documemts and articles; and various sound recordings.
Access
Collection is open for research. Listening appointments may require 24 hours notice. Contact the Archive Operations Manager.
Biography / Administrative History
Gary Hickling. Born Aug. 29, 1941. Lotte Lehmann discographer, performer and instructor of the double bass, radio show host for Hawaii Public Radio and founder of the Lotte Lehmann Foundation and Lotte Lehmann League. His discography of Lotte Lehmann appears in Beaumont Glass' biography "Lotte Lehmann: a life in opera and song", published by Capra Press in 1988. A more detailed biography may be found at: http://www.art-song.net/artsong/bios/bio_hickling.shtml.
Lotte Lehmann. Born Perleberg, Germany, Feb. 27, 1888; died Santa Barbara, Calif., Aug. 26, 1976. Operatic soprano. Lotte Lehmann began her career in Hamburg and moved to Vienna in 1916. She performed French, Italian and German roles for 15 years, primarily in Vienna and at Covent Garden, becoming especially known for the role of the Marschallin in Richard Strauss' Der Rosenkavalier. In 1938 she left Austria and settled in the United States where she performed primarily as a Lied singer. She retired from the stage in 1951, but continued very active as a much revered teacher in Santa Barbara, Calif.
Scope and Content of Collection
The collection includes Hickling's correspondence dealing with his discography, the Lotte Lehmann Archives at the University of California, Santa Barbara, and the Lotte Lehmann Centennial Celebrations at UCSB; A collection of articles, reviews and research notes for his discography; Photocopies of some of Lotte Lehmann's correspondence, her drawings and articles; and various unpublished sound recordings including private audio tape reels of Lotte Lehmann performances.
Arrangement
Organized into 7 series: I. Correspondence. II. Lotte Lehmann documents. III. Programs. IV. Articles. V. Research notes. VI. Organizations. VII. Recordings.
I. Correspondence: The letters addressed mainly to Gary Hickling deal mostly with inquiries related to the Lehmann discography. Among the many institutions from which Mr. Hickling received letters providing him with information are the Deutsches Musikarchiv in Berlin, the Salzburger Festspiele, the Deutsches Rundfunkarchiv in Frankfurt, the Sueddeutscher Rundfunk in Stuttgart, and the Westdeutscher Rundfunk in Cologne to name just a few. Most of these letters date from the late 1980s and early 90s.
II. Lotte Lehmann documents: Include some of her drawings on Der Rosenkavalier, recording contracts and promotional photographs which comprise Lehmann in various opera roles. Samplings of her own poems and several essays: In memory of Paul Ulanowsky; The Singing Actor; The Singing Actress Attacks Her Part; Twelve Singers and a Conductor; G?ring, the Lioness and I; In Memory of Arturo Toscanini.
III. Programs Opera/concert programs ranging from 1926-1990 and opera announcements.
IV. Journals and Magazines: Various journal and magazine articles on Lotte Lehmann such as, Opera Journal ?Lotte Lehmann ? a secret life?? By Alan Jefferson (1976); Lyrica ?Adieu a Lotte Lehmann? by Andre Tubeuf (1976); Soundings ?Some thoughts on the Magic of Courage and Metamorphosis. Hugo v. Hofmannsthal- Lotte Lehmann-Richard Strauss? by Richard Exner (1988); and Opera News ?The Lehmann Mystique? by John Coveney (1988).
V. Research Notes: Hickling's data on his Lehmann discography.
VI. Articles: Ranging from 1935 to 1992 these include reviews, reminiscences and obituaries.
VII. Organizations: Documents from organizations such as the Lotte Lehmann Foundation; the Lotte Lehmann League; the International Association of Sound Archives and the Association for Recorded Sound Collections of the Southern California Chapter.
VIII. Recordings: 8 12-inch sound pressings, 78 private audiocassettes, and 11 private audio tape reels of Lotte Lehmann performances, interviews, master classes and public talks. Commercial recordings from this collection are integrated into the ARS general collection; a complete list of recordings is available via the Stanford Digital Repository (see below).
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Lehmann, Lotte.; Lehmann, Lotte--Discography.; Hickling, Gary--Correspondence.; Sopranos (Singers)--Discography.; Operas--Excerpts.
Container List
- Oversize
  - (Othertype 15)
- Correspondence
  - A-C (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - D-E (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - F-G (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - H (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Holden, Frances (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - J (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - K-L (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - M (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Moran, William (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - N-P (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - R (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Documents
  - S (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - T-U (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - University of California Santa Barbara (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - University of California Santa Barbara, Office of the University Librarian (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - V-Z (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Unidentified (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - (Box 2)
  - (Box 2)
  - Lotte Lehmann Drawings (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Lotte Lehmann - Personal Documents (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Lotte Lehmann - Pictures - Photocopies and Clippings (Box 2, Folder 2.3)
  - Lotte Lehmann - Pictures - Prints (Box 2, Folder 2.4)
  - Lotte Lehmann - Pictures - Opera Roles (Box 2, Folder 2.5)
  - Lotte Lehmann - Writings (Box 2, Folder 2.6)
- Programs
  - Concert Programs I (Box 3, Folder 3.1)
  - Concert Programs II (Box 3, Folder 3.2)
  - Opera Announcements (Box 3, Folder 3.3)
  - Lotte Lehmann Centennial SymposiumMay 28-30, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 3.4)
- Journals and magazines
  - Opera Journal1976 (Box 3, Folder 4.11)
  - Lyrica1976 (Box 3, Folder 4.12)
  - Soundings1988 (Box 3, Folder 4.13)
  - The Opera Quarterly1991 (Box 3, Folder 4.14)
  - Opera News1956, 1986, 1988,1989 (Box 3, Folder 4.15)
  - La Reata (Box 3, Folder 4.16)
  - Hope Ranch Park (Box 3, Folder 4.17)
  - The Magazine of Santa Barbara County (Box 3, Folder 4.18)
  - The Etude Music Magazine (Box 3, Folder 4.19)
  - Misc. Articles Dated I 1935-1975 (Box 4, Folder 4.2)
  - Misc. Articles Dated II1976-1992 (Box 4, Folder 4.3)
  - Articles Undated I (Box 4, Folder 4.4)
  - Articles Undated II (Box 4, Folder 4.5)
  - Articles - Obituaries (Box 4, Folder 4.6)
  - Articles - Reminiscences (Box 4, Folder 4.7)
  - Articles - Reviews (Box 4, Folder 4.8)
- Research notes
  - Research Notes - Addresses (Box 5, Folder 5.1)
  - Research Notes - Album and CD covers (Box 5, Folder 5.2)
  - Research Notes - Bibliographies (Box 5, Folder 5.3)
  - Research Notes - Discographies (Box 5, Folder 5.41)
  - Research Notes - Hickling Discographies (Box 5, Folder 5.42)
  - Research Notes - Huber Catalogue (Box 5, Folder 5.43)
  - Research Notes - Discographies - University of California Santa Barbara I (Box 5, Folder 5.441)
  - Research Notes - Discographies - University of California Santa Barbara II (Box 5, Folder 5.442)
  - Research Notes - Discographies - University of California Santa Barbara III (Box 5, Folder 5.443)
  - Research Notes - Discographies - University of California Santa Barbara IV (Box 5, Folder 5.444)
  - Research Notes - Hawaiian Victor Recordings (Box 6, Folder 5.5)
  - Research Notes - Library catalogue records (Box 6, Folder 5.6)
  - Research Notes - Radio broadcast and transcriptions (Box 6, Folder 5.7)
  - Research Notes - Misc. (Box 6, Folder 5.8)
- Organizations
  - Organizations - ARSC - SCC (Box 6, Folder 6.1)
  - Organizations - Lotte Lehmann Archive (Box 6, Folder 6.2)
  - Organizations - Lotte Lehmann Foundation (Box 6, Folder 6.3)
  - Organizations - Lotte Lehmann League (Box 6, Folder 6.4)
  - Organizations - IASA (Box 6, Folder 6.5)
  - Organizations - Stanford Archive of Recorded Sound (Box 6, Folder 6.6)
  - Organizations - Brochures and Commercial Catalogues I (Box 6, Folder 6.71)
  - Organizations - Brochures and Commercial Catalogues II. (Box 6, Folder 6.72)
- Recordings
  - Richard Strauss' 100th birthday -- Augsburg and Opera.1964, 1 sound tape cassette; stereo., 90 minutes (Othertype 7, Folder 1)
    ORF Radio Program. Members from the Vienna Philharmonic and the Vienna State Opera share their memories on Richard Strauss. Among them Otto Strasse (sp?) and Lotte Lehmann. (In German) -- Radio program: Augsburg und Oper with Heinz Fischer Karpin (sp?). Talk with "Kammersängerin" Lotte Lehmann after she was presented with the honor ring from the city of Vienna. (In German).
  - Musikliterarischen Studio.1968, 1 sound tape cassette; stereo., 90 minutes (Othertype 7, Folder 2)
    Radio Program. Celebrating Lotte Lehmann's 80th birthday. Gesangstyl in der Frühzeit der Schallplatte, text by Wolf Rosenberg. (In German)
  - Interview with Lotte Lehmann, 1968 -- Opera News on the Air, 1988., 1 sound tape cassette; stereo., 90 minutes (Othertype 7, Folder 3)
    Side A: Interview with Lotte Lehmann on June 25, 1968 in Bad Gastein, Austria. (In German). Side B: Radio program celebrating Lotte Lehmann's 100th birthday. Richard Moore (sp?) interviews Risa Stevens on her momories of Lehmann. (In English)
  - Interview with Lotte Lehmann, 1968 -- Richard Strauss' 100th birthday, 1964., 1 sound tape cassette; stereo., 90 minutes (Othertype 7, Folder 4)
    Side A: Interview with Lotte Lehmann on June 25, 1968 in Bad Gastein, Austria. (Duplicate. In German). Side B: Interview with Lotte Lehmann on her work with Richard Strauss. (In German)
  - Conversation with Lotte Lehmann, 1969., 1 sound tape cassette; stereo., 60 minutes (Othertype 7, Folder 5)
    Audio recording of TV program. Dr. Heinz Fischer Karvin (sp?) leads a discussion with Kammersänger, Alfred Järger (sp?), Berndt Wessling (author of the book Lotte Lehmann: mehr als eine Sängerin), and Lotte Lehmann. (In German, poor recording quality)
  - Unser Kulturinterview, 1973 -- Richard Strauss' 100th birthday, 1964., 1 sound tape cassette; stereo., 90 minutes (Othertype 7, Folder 6)
    ORF, Radio program. Frieder Jahri (sp?) interviews Lotte Lehmann. (In German) -- Interview with Lotte Lehmann on Richard Strauss. (In German)
  - Lotte Lehmann als Liedsängerin, 1988., 1 sound tape cassette; stereo., 90 minutes (Othertype 7, Folder 7)
    Radio program. Hertha Schuch discusses Lehmann's artistry as a Lied singer. Performer: Paul Ulanowsky, piano; Wien -- Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Erlkönig. Performer: Dr. Weismann, piano; Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856. Myrthen. Nussbaum. Performer: Bruno Walter, piano. Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856. Frauenliebe und Leben. Süsser Freund; An meinem Herzen, etc.
  - Weg der Musik: Die brennende Stimme, 1988., 1 sound tape cassette; stereo., 60 minutes (Othertype 7, Folder 8)
    Radio program announced by Alois Büche (sp?) for Lehmann's 100th birthday. (In German)
  - Lotte Lehmann's 100th birthday, 1988., 1 sound tape cassette; stereo., 60 minutes (Othertype 7, Folder 9)
    Audio recording of TV program. (In German, poor recording quality)
  - Lotte Lehmann's 100th birthday, 1988 -- Schöne Stimmen., 1 sound tape cassette; stereo., 90 minutes (Othertype 7, Folder 10)
    Oesterreichischer Rundfunk 2. Audio recording of TV program with Marcel Prawi on Lehmann's professional life -- Bayern 4. Radio Program. Schöne Stimmen
  - On Lotte Lehmann's 100th birthday, 1988., 1 sound tape cassette; stereo., 90 and 60 minutes (Othertype 7, Folder 11)
    Lecture by Marcel Prawi (In German, poor recording quality)
  - On Lotte Lehmann's 100th birthday, 1988., 1 sound tape cassettes; stereo., 90 and 60 minutes (Othertype 7, Folder 12)
  - On Lotte Lehmann in Vienna, 1988., 1 sound tape cassette; stereo., 90 minutes (Othertype 7, Folder 13)
    Lecture by Marcel Prawi (In German)
  - Das Phonomuseum Kostbaren aus den Archiven: Lehmann als Liedsängerin, 1988., 1 sound tape cassette; stereo., 90 minutes (Othertype 7, Folder 14)
    OEF Radio program hosted by Gottfried Kraus. Performer: Bruno Walter, piano. Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856. Frauenliebe und Leben. Du Ring an meinem Finger Performer: Paul Ulanowsky, piano; Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Als Luise die Briefe ihres ungetreuen Liebhabers verbrannte; Abendempfindung -- Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Selections -- Refrainlieder. Männer sind méchant -- Erlkönig -- An die Musik, etc.
  - Das Phonomuseum Kostbaren aus den Archiven., 1 sound tape cassette; stereo., 60 minutes (Othertype 7, Folder 15)
    OEF. Radio program hosted by Hertha Schuch and Gottfried Kraus. Interview with Lehmann in one of her last trips to Austria. (In German, poor recording quality)
  - On Lotte Lehmann's 100th birthday I, 1988., 1 sound tape cassette; stereo., 60 minutes each (Othertype 7, Folder 16)
    OEF Five part radio program hosted by Clemens Hüsslinger (sp?). On Lotte Lehmann's 100th birthday. (In German)
  - On Lotte Lehmann's 100th birthday II, 1988., 1 sound tape cassettes; stereo., 60 minutes each (Othertype 7, Folder 17)
  - On Lotte Lehmann's 100th birthday III, 1988., 1 sound tape cassette; stereo., 60 minutes each (Othertype 7, Folder 18)
  - On Lotte Lehmann's 100th birthday IV, 1988., 1 sound tape cassette; stereo., 60 minutes each (Othertype 7, Folder 19)
  - On Lotte Lehmann's 100th birthday V, 1988., 1 sound tape cassette; stereo., 60 minutes each (Othertype 7, Folder 20)
  - Conversation with Horst Wahl, 1988., 1 sound tape cassette; stereo., 60 minutes (Othertype 7, Folder 21)
    Informal conversation with Horst Wahl and (possibly) Gary Hickling discussing Lehmann's discogrpahy. (In German).
  - Various Lehmann talks., 1 sound tape cassette; stereo., 90 minutes (Othertype 7, Folder 22)
    Side 1: Lehmann, Odeon reading -- Presentation of Vienna's honor ring with Franz Jonas and Lehmann's thank you speech, 1964 -- Hans Fischer Karwin interviews Lehmann on Wessling's book, 1969 -- HFK-TV program Salzburg, 1969. Side 2: Lehmann, Odeon reading (duplicate) -- Tribute -- Various excerpts. (In German)
  - Let's talk it over, Dec. 30, 1937., 1 sound tape cassette; stereo., 60 minutes (Othertype 7, Folder 23)
    Ms. Sergio (sp?) interviews Lehmann.
  - Magic key (Radio program)., 1 sound tape cassette; stereo., 90 minutes (Othertype 7, Folder 24)
    RCA and NBC. Magic key (Radio program), devoted to Lotte Lehmann.
  - Magic key (Radio program), Jan. 10, 1937., 1 sound tape cassette; stereo., 90 minutes (Othertype 7, Folder 25)
  - Magic key (Radio program), April 3, 1938., 1 sound tape cassette; stereo., 60 minutes (Othertype 7, Folder 26)
    RCA and NBC. Magic key (Radio program), devoted to Lotte Lehmann
  - Magic key (Radio program), Sept. 18, 1939., 1 sound tape cassette; stereo., 60 minutes (Othertype 7, Folder 27)
  - Lehmann, talk on her Vienna trip, 1955., 1 sound tape cassette; stereo., 60 minutes (Othertype 7, Folder 28)
  - Lehmann, talk on her Vienna trip, 1955., 1 sound tape cassette; stereo., 60 minutes (Othertype 7, Folder 29)
    (duplicate)
  - Literary Forum, 1959., 1 sound tape cassette; stereo., 60 minutes (Othertype 7, Folder 30)
    NYU radio committee in cooperation with WHN. Prof. Dorothy McF Arnold leads a discussion with Lotte Lehmann on her novel Eternal Flight.
  - Lecture demonstration with Paul Ulanowsky, 1967., 1 sound tape cassette; stereo., 90 minutes (Othertype 7, Folder 31)
    Lecture is divided in two parts: Ulanowsky's view on the Lied and coaching of Rebeca Berg (sp?) in Wolf, Hugo, 1860-1903. Italienisches Liederbuch. Du denks mit einem Fädchen.
  - BBC Interview with Lotte Lehmann, 1968., 1 sound tape cassette; stereo., 90 minutes (Othertype 7, Folder 32)
  - Interview with Lotte Lehmann., 1 sound tape cassette; stereo., 90 minutes (Othertype 7, Folder 33)
    BBC?
  - Conversation with Frances Holden and Kathy Brown, March 24, 1989., 1 sound tape cassette; stereo., 90 minutes (Othertype 7, Folder 34)
  - Lehmann master class at Music Academy of the West, Aug. 1952., 1 sound tape cassette; stereo., 90 minutes (Othertype 7, Folder 35)
    (poor recording quality)
  - Lehmann master class at Music Academy of the West, Aug. 1952., 1 sound tape cassette; stereo., 90 minutes (Othertype 7, Folder 36)
  - Lehmann master class at Music Academy of the West, Aug. 1952., 1 sound tape cassette; stereo., 90 minutes (Othertype 8, Folder 37)
  - Lehmann master class at Music Academy of the West, Aug. 1953., 1 sound tape cassette; stereo., 90 minutes (Othertype 8, Folder 38)
  - Lehmann master class at Music Academy of the West, Aug. 1953., 1 sound tape cassette; stereo., 90 minutes (Othertype 8, Folder 39)
  - Lehmann master class at Music Academy of the West, Aug. 1953., 1 sound tape cassette; stereo., 90 minutes (Othertype 8, Folder 40)
  - Lehmann master class at Music Academy of the West, Aug.1953., 1 sound tape cassette; stereo., 90 minutes (Othertype 8, Folder 41)
  - Lehmann master class at Music Academy of the West, Aug.1953., 1 sound tape cassette; stereo., 90 minutes (Othertype 8, Folder 42)
  - Lehmann master class at Music Academy of the West, Aug.1953., 1 sound tape cassette; stereo., 90 minutes (Othertype 8, Folder 43)
  - Lehmann master class at Northwestern University I, May 1967., 1 sound tape cassette; stereo., 90 minutes (Othertype 8, Folder 44)
    The Interpretation of Song.
  - Lehmann master class at Northwestern University II, May 1967., 1 sound tape cassette; stereo., 90 minutes (Othertype 8, Folder 45)
  - Lehmann master class at Northwestern University III, May 1967., 1 sound tape cassette; stereo., 90 minutes (Othertype 8, Folder 46)
  - Lehmann master class at Northwestern University IV, May 1967., 1 sound tape cassette; stereo., 90 minutes (Othertype 8, Folder 47)
  - Lehmann master class at Northwestern University V, May 1967., 1 sound tape cassette; stereo., 90 minutes (Othertype 8, Folder 48)
  - Lehmann master class at Northwestern University VI, May 1967., 1 sound tape cassette; stereo., 90 minutes (Othertype 8, Folder 49)
  - Lehmann master class at Northwestern University VII, May 1967., 1 sound tape cassette; stereo., 90 minutes (Othertype 8, Folder 50)
  - Lehmann master class at Northwestern University VIII, May 1967., 1 sound tape cassette; stereo., 90 minutes (Othertype 8, Folder 51)
  - Lehmann master class at Music Academy of the West, Jan. 27, 1968., 1 sound tape cassette; stereo., 90 minutes (Othertype 8, Folder 52)
  - Lehmann - Nelson's private lesson I., 1 sound tape cassette; stereo., 90 minutes (Othertype 8, Folder 53)
  - Lehmann - Nelson's private lesson II., 1 sound tape cassette; stereo., 90 minutes (Othertype 8, Folder 54)
  - Lehmann - Nelson's private lesson III., 1 sound tape cassette; stereo., 90 minutes (Othertype 8, Folder 55)
  - Lehmann - Nelson's private lesson IV., 1 sound tape cassette; stereo., 90 minutes (Othertype 8, Folder 56)
  - Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Winterreise., 1 sound tape cassette; stereo., 90 minutes (Othertype 8, Folder 57)
    Performer: Paul Ulanowsky, piano Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Winterreise
  - Lotte Lehmann, Lieder., 1 sound tape cassette; stereo., 90 minutes (Othertype 8, Folder 58)
    Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Traum durch die Dämmerung; Lieder, op. 56. Mit deinen blauen Augen -- Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Nacht und Träume
  - Lotte Lehmann, Lieder and folk songs., 1 sound tape cassette; stereo., 90 minutes (Othertype 8, Folder 59)
    Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856. An den Sonnenschein; Lieder-Album für die Jugend. Marienwürmchen -- Eine kleine Liebelei -- Frühling ist es wieder -- Bavarian folksong Zuschau'n, etc.
  - Lotte Lehmann, Town Hall Recital, Feb 27, 1949., 1 sound tape cassette; stereo., 90 minutes (Othertype 8, Folder 60)
    Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Selections -- Als Luise die Briefe ihres ungetreuen Liebhabers verbrannte -- Abendempfindung -- Dans un bois solitaire -- Verschweigung -- Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897. Selections -- Lieder und Gesänge, op. 59. Dein blaues Auge -- Lieder, op. 97. Komm bald -- Bitteres zu sagen -- Lieder, op. 95. Schön war, das ich dir weihte -- Lieder, op. 49. Am Sonntag Morgen -- Lieder, op. 48. Gang zum Liebchen -- Lieder, op. 96. Tod, das ist die kühle Nacht -- Gesänge, op. 3. Liebestreu -- Gesänge, op. 6. Frühling -- Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Kuss -- Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897. O wüsst' ich doch den Weg zurück; Romanzen aus L. Tiecks Magelone. Wie froh und frisch.
  - Lotte Lehmann, Lieder (not on LP)., 1 sound tape cassette; stereo., 90 minutes (Othertype 8, Folder 61)
    Gounod, Charles, 1818-1893. Faust. Il était un roi de Thulé -- Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847. Gesänge, op. 34. Auf Flügeln des Gesanges; Freiheit die ich meine -- Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Selections -- Veilchen -- Dans un bois solitaire -- Abendempfindung -- Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897. Romanzen aus L. Tiecks Magelone. Wie froh und frisch -- Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Ich denke dein, voice, piano; Gesänge, op. 75. Neue Liebe neues Leben -- Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847. Lieder, op. 71. Schilflied -- Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856. Liederkreis, op. 39. Stille -- Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847. Gesänge (1835). Pagenlied -- Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Winterreise. Frühlingstraum.
  - Lotte Lehmann, Lieder (not on LP)., 1 sound tape cassette; stereo., 90 minutes (Othertype 8, Folder 62)
    Side 1: Heiligtum des Herzens -- Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. Schwanengesang (Song cycle). Ständchen -- An den Mond, D. 193 -- Jüngling an der Quelle -- An die Nachtigall, D. 497 -- Schumann, Robert, 1810-1856. Selections -- Gedichte, op. 35. Alte Laute -- Myrthen. Du bist wie eine Blume -- Liederkreis, op. 39. Frühlingsnacht -- Franz, Robert, 1815-1892. Gesänge, op. 10. Für Musik; Gesänge, op. 5. Gute Nacht --Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897. Selections -- Lieder und Gesänge, op. 32. Wie bist du, meine Königin -- Lieder, op. 96. Wir wandelten -- Lieder, op. 46. An die Nachtigall -- Lieder, op. 105. Auf dem Kirchhofe -- Deutsche Volkslieder, WoO 35. Selections -- Erlaube mir -- Deutsche Volkslieder, WoO 35. Da unten im Tale -- Deutsche Volkslieder, WoO 33. Feinsliebchen, du sollst -- Lieder, op. 47. Sonntag -- Lieder, op. 47. O liebliche Wangen -- Gesänge, op. 43. Mainacht (incomplete). Side 2: Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897. Gesänge, op. 43. Mainacht -- Meyer-Helmund, Erik, 1861-1932. Lieder, op. 21. Zauberlied -- Dir Herr -- Wo Du hingehst -- Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Wesendonck-Lieder. Im Treibhaus -- Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828. An die Musik; Sei mir gegrüsst! -- Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Lieder, op. 27. Cäcilie --Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Tannhäuser. Dich, teure Halle -- Lehár, Franz, 1870-1948. Eva. Wär' es auch nichts als ein Augenblick -- Strauss, Johann, 1825-1899. Zigeunerbaron.
  - Lotte Lehmann, Lieder (not on LP)., 1 sound tape cassette; stereo., 90 minutes (Othertype 8, Folder 63)